Altay Aydemir

Email: altay@zebrastik.com

Website: altay.wtf

Summary

I'm a software engineer with 6+ years of experience, mostly focused on the user-facing side of the digital products. I enjoy transforming an idea into something tangible if it's solving a problem I empathize with.

Technical Background

Industries: Media Streaming, Cloud Storage, Blockchain, FinTech

Interests: Functional Programming, Domain-Driven Design, Humane Product Design

Languages: JavaScript, TypeScript, Swift, Kotlin (beginner)

Runtimes and Platforms: NodeJS, web, iOS, tvOS, Android, LG webOS, Samsung Tizen, Roku,

Chromecast

Buzzwords: React, React Native, CSS-in-JS, Design Systems, Storybook, Visual Testing, Jest, GraphQL,

Webpack, Docker, Fastlane, Apache Kafka

Work Experience

Software Engineer at put.io [Jan 2022 - Now]

After three years in Berlin, I took a break from work and moved to a warm seaside district (Bodrum) in Turkey to lighten the psychological effects of the pandemic.

I've also re-started working full-time at put.io, which I've been a part of since 2017 and kept working as a consultant when I moved to Berlin in 2018.

Nowadays I'm working on our web, iOS, tvOS and Android TV applications.

Software Engineer at Klarna (Berlin, Germany) [May 2019 - August 2021]

Senior Engineer at Consumer Deals (01.2020 - 08.2021)

Switched to a product team focusing on Shopping Growth that I built the MVP back in 2019.

On-boarded new hires, led the front-end feature development and cross-team integrations.

Senior Engineer at App Client Core (01.2020 - 01.2021)

Got promoted to Senior Engineer and switched to a distributed team (Stockholm, Berlin, Amsterdam) that is responsible for the integrity, performance, security and the release cycle of the consumer application, which is live in 14 countries with average 6M daily active users.

Restructured the localization architecture of the app to support 10+ languages with different dialects.

Altay Aydemir

Worked on a package based feature isolation project in the monorepo to allow product teams to develop their features in a safe and standardized way.

Built a dashboard for managing the killswitch behavior and monitoring releases of the consumer apps.

Helped new joiners to on-board Klarna App ecosystem, reviewed 300+ pull-requests from 50+ teams.

Did code reviews and interviews for JavaScript hiring pipeline.

Engineer at Consumer Growth and Loyalty - Marketing Touchpoint Infrastructure (06.2019 - 01.2020)

Integrated native SDKs of the 3rd party analytics and marketing platforms to the consumer facing app.

Developed several loyalty related campaign infrastructures by using Kafka, NodeJS and React.

On-boarded new members to the ecosystem by organising workshops and tutorials.

Frontend Engineer at Lightcurve GmbH (Berlin, Germany) [Nov 2018 - May 2019]

Worked on the cross-platform Lisk Mobile app, built with React Native.

Implemented Bitcoin support according to BIP49 standard.

Developed native modules by using Swift.

Software Engineer at put.io (Istanbul, Turkey) [Jan 2017 - Now]

Worked in a small team consisting of three engineers (2 backend + 1 frontend).

Took full responsibility on the client-facing applications of the product.

Maintained and implemented new features to the existing web app.

Built a proof-of-concept iOS app with React Native, then iterated on the v2 with Swift which includes features such as Chromecast and downloading media for offline consumption.

Developed an Apple TV application with Swift, TVML and TVMLJSKit.

Developed web-based Smart TV applications for Samsung Tizen, LG WebOS, AndroidTV and Amazon FireTV platforms.

Developed a Roku application with BrightScript.

Built cross-browser extensions with WebExtensions API.

Automated build and deployment processes by using Fastlane, Jenkins and TravisCI.

Frontend Engineer at Vispera (Istanbul, Turkey) [Sep 2016 - Mar 2017]

Re-designed and structured the front-end layer of the core Rails application.

Built single-page apps for complex data entry and management purposes with React.

Altay Aydemir 3

Frontend Engineering Intern at Peergust (Istanbul, Turkey) [Mar 2016 - Sep 2016]

Built demo apps and content management panel for testing and marketing purposes of the P2P content delivery network by using React.

Education

BSc. Mechanical Engineering, Istanbul Bilgi University. (2012 - 2016)

Graduated in the 2nd place of the department with 2.90 GPA.

Last updated: May 2, 2023